{
    "data":[
    { "id":21,
      "question":"Where to see system logs?",
      "answer":"You can find these logs in /var/syslog file.",
      "link":""
    },
    { "id":22,
      "question":"In systemd systems how can you see the logs after last bootup?",
      "answer":"You can use this command. journalctl -b",
      "link":""
    },
    { "id":23,
      "question":"Where can you see information on what users logged into the system?",
      "answer":"You can find these infomation in lastlog which is located at /var/lastlog",
      "link":""
    },
    { "id":24,
      "question":"How to check the directories which are using most space?",
      "answer":"You can use this command. du -sch *",
      "link":""
    },
    { "id":25,
      "question": "How to see number of files that are opened by OS?",
      "answer":"You can use this command. lsof| wc -l",
      "link":""
    },
    { "id":26,
        "question": "Which command does not apply to a folder out of these: cat, file, rm -r, ls",
        "answer":"cat",
        "link":""
    },
    { "id":27,
        "question": "What does free command use for?",
        "answer":"This command is used for check the memory usage status in linux.",
        "link":""
    },
    { "id":28,
        "question": "How to see listening ports on linux?",
        "answer":"ss -l will list all the listening ports",
        "link":""
    },
    { "id":29,
        "question": "How can you take tcp dump?",
        "answer":"You can use tcp dump utility to take the TCP dump.",
        "link":""
    },
    { "id":30,
        "question": "How to list files and directories on reverse order of time?",
        "answer":"ls -ltr",
        "link":""
    }
  ]
}
  
